<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-option library="SearchPanes">
	<name>columns.searchPanes.threshold</name>
	<summary>Set the minimum number of unique values needed in a specific column to display that pane</summary>
	<since>SearchPanes 1.0.0</since>

	<type type="Decimal">
		<description>
            By setting the `-init columns.searchPanes.threshold` option to an decimal number of value less than one and greater than 0 it is possible to alter the point at which the pane for this column is displayed.
        </description>
	</type>

	<default value="0.6">
        The default value for the `-init searchPanes.threshold` paramater is `0.6`, this will be the default value for all of the columns unless otherwise specified by either `-init searchPanes.thresold` or `-init columns.searchPanes.threshold`. When this default value is in place it will mean that columns where the ratio of different values in the column to total rows is less than `0.6` then the pane will be shown. If the value is overwritten then if the ratio is less than that value then the pane will be shown.
	<description>
		<![CDATA[
        As standard columns must have a uniqueness ratio of 0.6 (ratio of different values throughout the column to the number of total rows).

        By setting the `-init columns.searchPanes.threshold` option to a different decimal value, the uniqueness ratio must be less than this value to display the pane for the column specified.

        This is useful as it allows fine tuning of at what point it is useful to show the pane for the specified column. If you were to always show a pane for tables with lots of columns the searching may become confusing. This adjustment allows searchPanes to internally make the decisions to display a simpler, less cluttered user interface which may otherwise arise if this was absent.

        The `-init columns.searchPanes.threshold` option is not the only option that affects pane displays, `-init searchPanes.minRows` also plays a part.

        The threshold of the uniqueness ratio can also be set for all of the columns by making use of the `-init searchPanes.threshold` option.

        If you desire to force specific panes to show and other specific panes to hide without having searchPanes automatically work it out, make use of the `-init columns.searchPanes.show` option.
        ]]>
	</description>

	<example title="Change the threshold of the uniqueness ratio for a specific column"><![CDATA[

$(document).ready(function() {
    $('#example').DataTable( {
        dom: 'Sfrtip',
        columnDefs:[
            {
                searchPanes:{
                    threshold: 0.99,
                },
                targets:[0]
            },
        ],
    });
});

]]></example>

<related>-init columns.searchPanes.show</related>
<related>-init searchPanes.threshold</related>

</dt-option>
