<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-option library="SearchPanes">
	<name>columns.searchPanes.show</name>
	<summary>Force Panes to hide or show</summary>
	<since>SearchPanes 1.0.0</since>

	<type type="boolean">
		<description>
            By setting the `-init columns.searchPanes.show` option to true for a column, a pane for that column will be shown even if the threshold calculations would reject it.

			Equally, by setting the `init columns.searchPanes.show` option to be false for a column, a pane for that column will not be regardless of the threshold calculations.
        </description>
	</type>

	<default value="undefined">
        The default value for the `-init searchPanes.show` paramater is `-type undefined`. When this default value is in place, the internal calculations and validation will decide whether a pane should be shown for that column. See `-init searchPanes.thershold` and `-init columns.searchPanes.threshold` to alter these calculations.
    </default>
	<description>
		<![CDATA[
        As standard, SearchPanes will decide which columns to display a pane for by calculating a simple uniqueness ratio of unique values in that column to the total number of entries in the table. For example if there are 100 rows in a table, and in a certain column there are 10 unique options, then the ratio is 0.1.
		
		If the calculated value is less than the default threshold for all of the panes then this column will have a pane (assuming that the threshold has not been altered for all or an individual row by either `-init searchPanes.threshold` or `-init columns.searchPanes.threshold`).

		The `-init columns.searchPanes.show` option is useful for removing this calculation from the process and effectively forcing a pane to either be shown or hidden.

		The example forces a pane to be displayed for the first column and the pane for the third column to be hidden. 
        ]]>
	</description>

	<example title="Force panes to hide and show"><![CDATA[

$(document).ready(function() {
    $('#example').DataTable( {
        dom: 'Sfrtip',
        columnDefs:[
            {
                searchPanes:{
                    show: true,
                },
                targets: [0],
            },
            {
                searchPanes:{
                    show: false,
                },
                targets: [2],
            }
        ]
    });
});

]]></example>

<related>-init searchPanes.threshold</related>
<related>-init columns.searchPanes.threshold</related>

</dt-option>
